Mss.Rec.37 Mss.Rec.37
American Philosophical Society
Upper Chehalis (Salish) language material
1960
Mss.Rec.37
American Philosophical Society
5.0 Tape(s)
Word lists and grammatical eliciting; folkloric stories and narratives pertaining to Chehalis history; Quinault medicine-man text; and four Lower Cowlitz words. Recorded at Grand Mound, Washington, in July 1960.
5 sound tape reels (9 hr., 58 min.): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
Heck, Silas
Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by M. Dale Kinkade in 1961. This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Chehalis Indians--Folklore; Chehalis Indians--History; Indians of North America--Washington (State); Sound recordings; Upper Chehalis language
- Audio recordings
  - Upper Chehalis word list, 1960-07; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:42:24; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Scope and Contents note
    Recorded at Grand Mound, Washington.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Grand Mound (Wash.); Upper Chehalis language
  - Wren & Otter text, 1960-07; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:04; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Told in entirety in Upper Chehalis, then given in English.
    Birds--Folklore; Chehalis Indians--Folklore; Grand Mound (Wash.); Raven (Legendary character)--Legends; Upper Chehalis language; Wrens--Folklore
  - Upper Chehalis grammatical eliciting, 1960-07; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:48; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Grand Mound (Wash.); Upper Chehalis language; Upper Chehalis language--Grammar
  - Upper Chehalis grammatical eliciting, 1960-07; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:49:16; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
  - 4th of July text, 1960-07; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:14; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Chehalis Indians; Fourth of July; Grand Mound (Wash.); Upper Chehalis language
  - Upper Chehalis grammatical eliciting, 1960-07; 01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:10; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
  - Upper Chehalis grammatical eliciting, 1960-07; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:06:15; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
  - Upper Chehalis grammatical eliciting, 1960-07; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:53:51; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
  - Upper Chehalis grammatical eliciting, 1960-07; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:02; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
  - Quinault medicine man text, 1960-07; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:45; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Chehalis Indians--Folklore; Grand Mound (Wash.); Quinault Indians; Upper Chehalis language
  - Upper Chehalis grammatical eliciting, 1960-07; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:56; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
  - Upper Chehalis grammatical eliciting, 1960-07; 03-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:55:06; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
  - Story of the flood, 1960-08; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:56; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Chehalis Indians--Folklore; Floods; Grand Mound (Wash.); Upper Chehalis language
  - Story of the sun and the moon, 1960-08; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:35:56; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Chehalis Indians--Folklore; Grand Mound (Wash.); Moon--Folklore; Sun--Folklore; Upper Chehalis language
  - Political speech, 1960-08; 04-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:11; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Chehalis Indians--Politics and government; Grand Mound (Wash.); Speeches, addresses, etc.; Upper Chehalis language
  - Xu'en and the chief's daughter, 1960-08; 04-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:14; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Chehalis Indians--Folklore; Grand Mound (Wash.); Upper Chehalis language
  - Upper and Lower Chehalis battle, 1960-08; 04-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:06; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Battles; Chehalis Indians--History; Grand Mound (Wash.); Upper Chehalis language
  - Upper Chehalis grammatical eliciting, 1960-08; 04-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:57:24; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
  - Bluejay's Trip text, 1960-08; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:44; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Blue jay--Folklore; Chehalis Indians--Folklore; Grand Mound (Wash.); Upper Chehalis language
  - Hunter & Baby text, 1960-08; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:56; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Story of a hunter who found a baby boy in a hollow tree.
    Chehalis Indians--Folklore; Grand Mound (Wash.); Hunters--Folklore; Upper Chehalis language
  - Cougar & his 5 Brothers text, 1960-08; 05-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:22; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Chehalis Indians--Folklore; Grand Mound (Wash.); Puma--Folklore; Upper Chehalis language
  - White men at Mud Bay text, 1960-08; 05-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:56; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Chehalis Indians--History; Eld Inlet (Wash.); Grand Mound (Wash.); Upper Chehalis language
  - Wren & Snipe text, 1960-08; 05-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:47; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
    Birds--Folklore; Chehalis Indians--Folklore; Grand Mound (Wash.); Upper Chehalis language; Wrens--Folklore
  - Upper Chehalis grammatical eliciting, 1960-08; 05-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:35; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
  - Upper Chehalis grammatical eliciting, 1960-08; 05-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:34:58; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
  - Wren & Elk text, 1960-08; 05-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:52; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-
  - Upper Chehalis grammatical eliciting, 1960-08; 05-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:59; Heck, Silas; Kinkade, M. Dale (Marvin Dale), 1933-